<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Release on olaFlow | CFD for waves</title>
    <link>https://olaflow.github.io/tags/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Release on olaFlow | CFD for waves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:20:40 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://olaflow.github.io/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing olaFlow</title>
      <link>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/releasing-olaflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:20:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/releasing-olaflow/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost two years since I released olaFoam, after finishing my PhD and starting a new postdoc at the National University of Singapore. In this time I have added functionalities (piston and flap wavemakers, simultaneous wave and current generation, additional wave theories&amp;hellip;), increased performance and compatibility, and fixed bugs. Today I continue walking ahead towards a bigger project.
It is my pleasure to introduce olaFlow CFD suite, the new evolution in active wave generation and absorption frameworks in OpenFOAM®.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OLAFOAM release, the evolution of IHFOAM</title>
      <link>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/olafoam-release-the-evolution-of-ihfoam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 12:20:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/olafoam-release-the-evolution-of-ihfoam/</guid>
      <description>This is an old post saved for archival purposes only. The olaFoam project is now the olaFlow project OLAFOAM is the evolution of IHFOAM, a well-known three-dimensional Navier-Stokes solver for free surface flows, and is born with the spirit of providing the latest advances for the simulation of wave dynamics to the OpenFOAM and FOAM-extend communities.
At this initial stage OLAFOAM is a slightly modified version of IHFOAM, but new implementations and updates (see roadmap in the wiki site) will be readily available soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>