<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWA on olaFlow | CFD for waves</title>
    <link>https://olaflow.github.io/tags/awa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWA on olaFlow | CFD for waves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:20:40 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://olaflow.github.io/tags/awa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Range Active Wave Absorption has just been published</title>
      <link>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/extended-range-active-wave-absorption-has-just-been-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:20:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/extended-range-active-wave-absorption-has-just-been-published/</guid>
      <description>Today we are glad to announce that Enhancing active wave absorption in RANS models has just been published at Applied Ocean Research.
You can access the paper for free during the first 50 days using the following link:
https://authors.elsevier.com/a/1a7UkW5Z38f%7EE
Enhancing active wave absorption in RANS models In this work we review the most common methods for absorbing waves in Reynolds-Averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) models. The limitations of active wave absorption, originating from its initial assumption of linear wave theory in shallow waters are overcome and the range of applicability is extended to any relative water depth conditions by re-deriving the formulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New branch added to olaFlow</title>
      <link>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/new-branch-added-to-olaflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 12:20:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/new-branch-added-to-olaflow/</guid>
      <description>Today we have an important announcement for the olaFlow community. The long wait to have access to the Extended Range Active Wave Absorption (ER-AWA) introduced in our previous post is over.
The traditional AWA (SW-AWA) is based on the shallow water approximation for linear wave theory, thus, it does not perform well in intermediate and deep water conditions because it produces reflections above 20%. ER-AWA reduces the number of initial assumptions, since it is based on the general linear wave theory, valid at any water depth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active wave absorption enhancements in olaFlow</title>
      <link>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/active-wave-absorption-enhancements-in-olaflow-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 12:20:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olaflow.github.io/blog/active-wave-absorption-enhancements-in-olaflow-copy/</guid>
      <description>Today we are glad to present you Enhancing active wave absorption in RANS models, our new preprint, soon to be published:
Enhancing active wave absorption in RANS models In this work we review the most common methods for absorbing waves in Reynolds-Averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) models. The limitations of active wave absorption, originating from its initial assumption of linear wave theory in shallow waters are overcome and the range of applicability is extended to any relative water depth conditions by re-deriving the formulation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>